Ada Pedersen

Software Architect with a passion for creating simple, efficient and scalable solutions.

email@adapdr.me

📆 github.com/adapdr

in linkedin.com/in/adapdr

(+31 (0) 622 935 677

Dordrecht, The Netherlands

EXPERIENCE

Software Architect/Engineer @ Karla

Sep 2022 - April 15 2023

Lead the (re)design of the backend system architecture for the core company product, configured and managed product infrastructure and integration of essential third-party APIs and other services.

Software/Technical Architect @ Pixie Interactive

Nov 2021 - August 2022

Worked directly alongside the CTO with a small team on the design, planning and development of the core company product while leading the development on several external & internal services. Notably with a focus on modern, open-source technologies.

Additionally managed multiple area's of DevOps including: Hosting, Backups, Security, GDPR, Automations and more.

Head of infrastructure including DevOps responsibilities like backups, security, GDPR, automations++.

Software Engineer @ Experience Data

Aug 2021 - February 2022

Lead the modernization of the technology stack and worked together with management & data scientists to create new and improved development standards & workflows.

Co-development on a variety of company products and services in a Developer/ DevOps capacity.

* Please note that **only** the last 3 positions/contracts are listed for the purpose of keeping this document concise.

Technologies & tools

OpenAPI, REST, FastAPI, Masonite, Dash, Flask/ Django, Pandas, BS4, Pydantic, OAuth, AsyncIO, Pytest(asgi), WebTest, Maria/MySQL, Redis, Web3, Rethink, Postgress dbs++

Git(Hub/Lab), Docker, Traefik, Drone Cl, Postman, Stoplight (...etc)

Industry Knowledge

FOSS, *NIX, APIs, DevTooling, Microservices, DDD, Agile, Scrum, Blockchain, Microservices, containers, virtualization, distributed systems (...etc)

Languages

Norwegian (native) English (fluent) Dutch (basic)

Platforms

DigitalOcean, AWS, GCP

Other

Open-source & self-hosting CyberSec (CTF) hobbyist Competitive Gamer





EDUCATION

Software Development (College)

Fontys University of Applied Sciences 2017 - 2019, Eindhoven, The Netherlands

Computer Engineering (BSc)

University of Agder 2016 - 2017, Grimstad, Norway

ICT-Service & Infrastructure (Trade Diploma)

Nordahl Grieg VGS | Dataoppdrag AS 2012 - 2015, Bergen, Norway

BACKGROUND

Software Dev & Ops

The majority of my professional development work has been in creating new and migrating older legacy systems using open-source tooling and scalable, distributed technologies.

This has meant extensive work with modern, containerized service and serverless technologies paired with DevOps tasks such as CI/CD management, automations, bots, and other developer workflow accelerating optimizations and improvements.

Primary language has been Python for the last 5 1/2 years professionally, and >10 years personally. Secondary language has recently been Rust to fill in specific low-level requirement features.

Software Tester

Before I went on to dedicated development work (and later ops) I breifly worked as a software tester working on the testing, documentation and verification of devices and software for the deployment of the Norwegian smart power grid. This later grew into a love for automation and static analysis tools for with Python.

SysAdmin & ICT

Started as a system administrator and consultant where I worked on deployment, monitoring and administration of and extensive amount of (windows/linux)servers, various third-party and client; CRM, mail(exchange), database, networking, firewall systems.